SANNIDHI SARVADHAVABHATLA

2230 Dwight Way APT 101, Berkeley, CA, 94704 847.226.5080 · sannidhi.sarva@gmail.com sannidhisarva.com · linkedin.com/in/sannidhisarva/

PROFILE

I am a senior majoring in Public Health at the University of California, Berkeley. I have experience in lab work, volunteering, and programming. I am interested in pursuing a career in the public health field, with a focus on chronic diseases.

EDUCATION

PUBLIC HEALTH MAJOR, UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, BERKELEY

AUGUST 2018 - MAY 2021

Relevant Coursework: Statistical Analysis of Categorical Variables; Introduction to Epidemiology and Human Diseases; Introduction to Probability and Statistics in Public Health; Introduction to Data Science; General Chemistry and Lab; General Biology and Lab; Organic Chemistry and Lab

SKILLS

- R, SAS, and Python
- Covered California Certified Health Insurance Enroller
- Literature review and PUBMED MeSH searches
- Basic understanding of Spanish (reading, writing, speaking)
- BLS and First Aid Certified with AHA
- MS Office and Google Suite

EXPERIENCE

STUDENT ASSISTANT, INNOVATIVE GENOMICS INSTITUTE | BERKELEY, CA

AUGUST 2020 - PRESENT

- Creating nasopharyngeal swab kits for the on-campus COVID-19 surveillance testing program
- Producing RNA tubes with reagent containing the primers for PCR analysis once the sample is collected
- Developing familiarity with health and safety protocols relating to COVID-19

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, BARCELLOS LAB | BERKELEY, CA

JULY 2020 - PRESENT

- Performing literature reviews regarding COVID-19 studies treatments, incidence, testing accuracy using PUBMED
- Generating reports of summary statistics, graphs, tables, and analysis using R on summary findings of literature reviews
- Developing strong analytical and search skills of complex published literature understanding the abstracts, procedures, and results. Updating on a weekly basis with graduate student, Mary Horton PhD Candidate
- Assisting with preparation of background information for the Introduction section of upcoming manuscripts pending publication regarding COVID-19
- Performing data entry on returned info cards with dates and time of blood and nasal swab sample collection
- Assembling kits that contain antibody blood samples and nasopharyngeal swabs to collect samples to better understand the Bay Area incidence of COVID-19, along with antibody prevalence

ER VOLUNTEER, UCSF BENIOFF CHILDREN'S HOSPITAL | OAKLAND, CA

APRIL 2019 – PRESENT

- Stock IV carts, transport patients to various diagnostic testing
- Assisting nurses with minor patient procedures comforting patients and handing necessary supplies
- Learning how to assess patient's profile with their electronic health records, understand complex medical terminology
- Developing key awareness of hospital systems and functions being responsive to urgent requests

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, BACHTROG LAB | BERKELEY, CA

APRIL 2019 – JUNE 2020

- Advanced strong microscope skills, basic laboratory safety skills, and wet lab skills (pipetting, transformations, cell cultures)
- Performed various microbiology skills: running PCRs, gels, and DNA/RNA extractions
- Worked with Drosophila to knockout proteins, screened for Green Fluorescent Protein (GFP)

EXTRACURRICULARS

CERTIFIED HEALTH INSURANCE ENROLLER, CALIFORNIA HEALTH PROFESSIONAL STUDENT ALLIANCE

AUGUST 2019 - PRESENT

- Participating in enrollment events in the fall and winter to help enroll local residents obtain coverage through COVERDCA
- Advocating to improve the quality & access to health care in California

COMMITTEE MEMBER. AMERICAN MEDICAL STUDENT ASSOCIATION

AUGUST 2019 - PRESENT

- Collaborating with the Race, Ethnicity, and Culture in Health and Gender and Sexuality (REACH/GS) committee where we spread awareness on health disparities; presented on disparities regarding organ transplants
- Increasing interest and passion for community service

COMMITTEE MEMBER, CAL UNDERGRADUTE PUBLIC HEALTH COALITION

JANUARY 2020 – JANUARY 2021

- Organized events to spread public health awareness as part of the International Health committee
- Hosted a tabling event on Sproul in March to spread information about COVID-19